

Michiel Roukens React Developer

Try me!

Contact

phone +31622040319 email info@arejo.nl location The Hague, Netherlands

github github portfolio portfolio linkedin LinkedIn

About me

Startup founder turned developer.

Extremely passionate about building beautiful, practical and smart things. Selfstarting, highly determined, obsessively persistent.

Having completed the Frontend section of the Full-Stack Career Course on codecademy, I am eager to practice my new found skills as a Front-end / React Developer.

Open for a junior position or Freelance assignment. Remote / hybrid preferred. Get in touch!

Experience

2021 - Current Arejas The Hague Becoming a Full-Stack JavaScript Developer
Bootcamp on Codecademy, Studying React / Express.
Build and sold a campervan to be able to study fulltime.
See: Education / About me.

2019/2022 Arejas The Hague

Wordpress websites & webshops for different clients using Divi, Elementor, WooCommerce, HTML and CSS.

2010-2019 mijnJohan.nl

Development, Marketing and Sales. Homegrown accountancy software for independent entrepreneurs. Passive Income Company.

2016-2017 Camptoo.nl The Hague

Growth Hacker

Freelance Developer

Head responsible for the growth of the product-offering for this peer-2-peer Campers & Caravans renting platform, using the complete online marketing spectrum including Goal Tracking, Analytics, Split Testing and Conversion Optimisation.

2015-2016 Yippie.nl Amsterdam

First marketing Officer

Head responsible for the first growth spurt in users of this shopping-app, using the complete online marketing spectrum including Facebook Ads, Google Ads, Goal Tracking, Analytics, Split Testing and Conversion Optimisation.

2011-2014 OWNR The Hague

Startup Founder

Internet startup in action sports. Responsible for marketing, sales, investors, product-development and allround succes. Collaborations with among others: Quiksilver / DC shoes and Nitro Snowboards.

Key Skills

нтмі

React

Redux

Node.js

GitHub

TDD Mocha JEST

JSON.

Express.js SQL

CSS JavaScript

Building web-apps from start to finish Rocking React & Redux

Education

2021 - Present

Full-Stack Developer Career Path Course

Becoming a Full-Stack web developer learning to build web-apps' front-end and back-end using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, Node, Express, SQL, TDD, Mocha, Jest, React Testing Library, Markdown, JSON, Git & Github.

2020 - 2021 codecademy

Build a back-end app with JavaScript

A predecessor to codecademy's back-end engineer career path. This was my introduction to JavaScript, Node, Express, SQL and building API's.

2008-2010 WdKa Rotterdam

Creative Advertising

 $\mbox{\sc Art Direction, concepting \& realisation.}$ Arts $\mbox{\sc Academy of Rotterdam.}$

1998-2004 Ashram College Alphen aan den Rijn

Atheneum

Atheneum. Focus on Economics & Society. Field of choice: Computer Science. Research paper: Encryption.

Marketing Skills

React Testing Library

Google Analytics
Goal Tracking
Growth Hacking Principles
Split Testing
Conversion Optimalisation
Google Adwords
Facebook Ads

Additional Skills

Adobe Creative Suite Google Sketchup SCRUM Agile

Certifications

 Back-end app with Javascript | Write API's with Node, Express & SQL | Codecademy | Jan '21

_anguages

Dutch

English

German

Spanish

Sno

Snowboard Skateboard Surf Wake Climbing Guitar Travel Campervans